Guide to the Vincent Cianni photographs, 1983-2012 RL.10038
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Vincent Cianni photographs
1983-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cianni, Vincent
RL.10038
21.5 Linear Feet 22 boxes 668 items
Vince Cianni is a documentary photographer based in Newburgh, New York. The Berlin series features photographs of East Berlin, the destruction of the Berlin Wall, and the reunification of Germany in 1990. The Poughkeepsie Mall and the Providence House Men's Shelter series both document urban culture and decay in the 1980s. The Weddings Series contains photographs from weddings (including some transgender) from the mid-1980s. The Brooklyn project features images and recorded interviews from Cianni's book, We Skate Hardcore, which relates to Hispanic American roller blade culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York, mid-1990s. Cambodian kickboxing culture is explored in another set of photographs taken in 2004. The last series offers a set of oral history interviews of gays in the military, also related to a photobook by Cianni. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research and educational, non-commercial use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Some digital media need reformatting before content can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Vincent Cianni photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as gifts and purchases from 2007-2010, and 2013.
Biographical Note
Vince Cianni is a documentary photographer based in Newburgh, New York.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises photographs from six bodies of documentary work by Vince Cianni, New York-based photographer and author. Subjects focus chiefly on American culture, exploring wedding rituals, skateboarding and youth culture, urban decay, street photography, shopping mall society, men in shelters, and gays in the military. There is also a series on kickboxing in Cambodia, and a large set of oral history interviews with gay men and women in the U.S. military. Most of the prints are gelatin silver, but there are also some in color.
Accession 2007-0072 houses a series of 224 black-and-white photographs depicting roller blade and Hispanic American youth street culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York, taken by Cianni during the 1990s and into 2001. Fifteen of the prints appear in Cianni's book, We Skate Hardcore: Photographs from Brooklyn's South Side (2001); and 68 prints are unpublished. Photographs are captioned and signed on the back. Also included are photographs of urban life in the Bronx, NY; and from the baby shower (Queens, NY) and wedding (Fairborn, OH) of a young couple who appear in other images from this series. Finally, the series houses the maquette for Cianni's book (version 1, 2000), and the printer's dummy (versions 2-3, 2001-2004).
Accession 2007-0200 contains 65 black-and-white prints and photographic collages of East Berlin, the destruction of the Berlin Wall and the reunification of Berlin, 1990. Prints range from 8x10 to 16x24 and are captioned and signed on back by the photographer.
Accession 2008-0048 contains prints from the Poughkeepsie Mall Series (Poughkeepsie, NY, 1980s) and the Providence House Men's Shelter Series (Newburgh, NY, 1983). Forty-four black-and-white photographic prints: one 5 5/8 x 8 ½; one 5 7/8 x9; and forty-two 11x14 prints. Poughkeepsie Mall series: twenty-two 11x14 prints, 1980s. The images depict youth culture, African American culture, and urban decay.
Accession 2008-0300 contains 184 prints of weddings, including some transexual weddings, taken by Cianni during the 1980s. This series includes Cianni's MFA project, Wedding Rituals, a group of twenty-four 20x24 prints and one 16x20 print. Photographs in this series are in both color and black-and-white; many are captioned and signed on the back by the photographer.
Accession 2008-0303 contains an additional 23 8x10 duotone and gelatin silver prints from Cianni's book We Skate Hardcore: Photographs from Brooklyn's South Side. These prints include portraits and other images of Hispanic American youth roller blade culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York during the mid-1990s.
Accession 2009-0243 houses forty-two black-and-white photographs of Muay Thai style of kickboxing competition in Siem Reap, Cambodia, 2004: thirty-six 8x10 prints and six 16x20 prints.
Accession 2010-0187 includes forty-seven 8x10 black-and-white prints from the We Skate Hardcore series. The gelatin silver prints are signed on verso and date 1995-2003, with bulk dates 1995-1997.
In addition, the collection contains digital video, stills, and image scans, and oral history recordings, all relating to his documentary photobooks We skate hardcore and Gays in the military. Original media formats are closed to use. Most files have been mounted to the library server; for access, please contact the Rubenstein Library.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Related Material
Photobook (see Duke University Libraries catalog): We skate hardcore: photographs from Brooklyn's Southside. Duke University Press, 2004.
Photobook (see Duke University Libraries catalog): Gays in the military: photographs and interviews by Vincent Cianni. Daylight Books, 2014.
Audiovisual materials; African Americans -- Social conditions; Berlin Wall, Berlin, Germany, 1961-1989 -- Pictorial works; Cities and towns -- United States; Documentary Photography -- United States; Hispanic Americans -- New York (State); In-line skating -- New York State -- New York -- Photographs; Kickboxing -- Cambodia; Martial arts -- Cambodia; Transgender people -- United States; Weddings -- Pictorial works; Youth -- United States -- Social conditions; Berlin (Germany) -- History -- 1945-1990 -- Pictorial works; Bronx (New York, N.Y.) -- Photographs; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions; Germany (East) -- Pictorial works; New York (State) -- Photographs; New York (State) -- Social conditions; Newburgh (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Poughkeepsie (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Queens (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Black-and-white photographs; CD-Rs; Digital audio formats; DVDs; Gelatin silver prints; Machine-readable artifacts; Mini-DV; Oral histories (document genre); Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Cianni, Vincent
- Berlin, 1990, 4 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Accession (2007-0200) contains 65 gelatin silver prints and photographic collages of East Berlin, the destruction of the Berlin Wall, and the reunification of Berlin, 1990. Print range in size from 8x10 to 16x24 and are captioned and signed on back by photographer.
  - Berlin prints (Box 1-4)
- Poughkeepsie Mall, 1980s, and Providence House Men's Shelter, 1983, 2 boxes
  Accession (2008-0048) contains prints from the Poughkeepsie Mall series (Poughkeepsie, NY, 1980s) and the Providence House Men's Shelter (Newburgh, NY, 1983). There are 44 black and white photographic prints: one 5 5/8 x 8 ½; one 5 7/8 x 9; and forty-two 11x14 prints. The Poughkeepsie Mall series contains twenty-two 11x14 prints shot in the 1980s. Images depict American youth culture, African American culture, and urban decay.
  - Poughkeepsie Mall and Providence House prints (Box 5-6)
- Weddings, 1980s, 5 boxes
  Accession (2008-0300) contains 184 prints of weddings, including some transexual weddings, taken by Cianni during the 1980s. This series includes Cianni's MFA project, Wedding Rituals, a group of twenty-four 20x24 prints and one 16x20 print. Photographs in this series are in both color and black and white; many are captioned and signed on the back by the photographer.
  - Wedding Rituals MFA project:, 24 20x24 black and white photographs, 1 16x20 black and white photograph (Box 7)
  - Transexual weddings:, 16 (16x20) black and white photographs (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous:, 11 (16x20) black and white photographs (Box 8)
  - Tom and Alison's wedding, Rockville Center, New York:, 18 (8x10) black and white photographs (Box 9)
  - Ring bearers at Pat Devaney's wedding, Cape May, New Jersey, 1983:, 3 (8x10) black and white photographs (Box 9)
  - Knowles/Mortimer wedding, Canadaigua, New York:, 22 (8x10) black and white photographs (Box 9)
  - Kaplan/Kreiger wedding, New York City, 1989:, 16 (8x10) black and white photographs (Box 10)
  - Kaplan/Kreiger wedding snapshots:, 12 (3x5) color photographs (Box 10)
  - Kershaw wedding, Clinton Corners, New York, 1987:, 5 (5x7) black and white photographs (Box 10)
  - Laura and Edmund's wedding, West Orange, New Jersey, 1991:, 7 (5x7) black and white photographs (Box 10)
  - Taylor/Kahene wedding, Cape May, New Jersey, 1986:, 5 (5x7) black and white photographs, 5 (3x5) color photographs (Box 10)
  - Weddings:, 38 (11x14) black and white photographs, 1 (6.75x14.5) black and white photograph (Box 11)
- Brooklyn / We Skate Hardcore, 1990s-2004 and undated; 7 boxes
  Accession (2007-0072) houses a series of 224 black-and-white photographic prints chiefly of Hispanic American youth roller blade and street culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York, shot by Cianni during the 1990s and into 2001. Many of the prints appear in Cianni's book, We Skate Hardcore: Photographs from Brooklyn's South Side (2001), and a number of prints are unpublished. Photographs are captioned and signed on the back. Also included are photographs of urban life in the Bronx, NY; and from the baby shower in Queens, NY, and the wedding in Fairborn, Ohio of a young couple who appear in other images from this series. Finally, the series houses the maquette for Cianni's book (version 1, 2000), and the printer's dummy (versions 2-3, 2001-2004).
  Accession (2008-0303) contains twenty-three 8x10 duotone and gelatin silver prints from Cianni's book We Skate Hardcore, and includes portraits and other images of Hispanic American youth roller blade culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York, during the mid-1990s.
  Accession (2010-0187) includes forty-seven 8x10 black-and-white gelatin silver prints from the We Skate Hardcore series. The prints are signed and date from 1995-2003, with most dating from the period 1995-1997.
  A set of digital materials with interviews, a video, video stills, and other supporting materials related to the photobook We Skate Harcore rounds out the series.
  - Accession (2008-0303)
    - Brooklyn:, 23 (8x10) black and white prints (Box 12)
  - Accession (2007-0072)
    - Brooklyn:, 83 black and white (8x10) prints, published and unpublished (Box 13)
    - Brooklyn:, 37 black and white (11x14) published prints (Box 14)
    - Brooklyn:, 36 black and white (11x14) unpublished prints (Box 15)
    - Brooklyn:, 68 black and white (11x14) unpublished prints (Box 16)
    - Brooklyn: Maquette, version 1 (Box 17)
    - Brooklyn: Printer's dummy, version 2-3 (Box 18)
  - Accession (2010-0187)
    - Brooklyn:, 47 black and white (8x10) prints, signed on verso (Box 21)
  - Digital material, 2001-2004 and undated
    CD-Rs, Mini-DV (digital video), and digital audio discs containing video stills, scans, interviews, and a video created by Vincent Cianni, all relating to the We Skate Hardcore project. Some paper prints of images are included with the CDs. Most files of scans have been mounted to the library server.
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Original media are closed to use. For access to these materials, please contact the Rubenstein Library Research Services staff in advance.
    - Digital media (9 CD-Rs, 1 Mini-DV - video, 3 mini-discs - audio) (Box 18)
- Cambodian Boxers, 2004, 2 boxes
  Accession (2009-0243) contains 42 gelatin silver prints depicting the Muay Thai style of kickboxing competition in Siem Reap, Cambodia 2004. The prints are arranged in three groupings by the photographer: a sequence of 21 8x10 prints; a sequence of 15 8x10 prints; and six 16x20 prints.
  - 8x10 black and white prints (Box 19)
    - Muay Thai, Siem Reap, part 1, 21 black and white prints (Box 19)
    - Muay Thai, Siem Reap, part 2, 15 black and white prints (Box 19)
  - 16x20 prints, Muay Thai, Siem Reap, 6 black and white prints (Box 20)
- Gays in the Military - Interviews, 2010-2012; 1
  Scope and Contents
  From 2009 to 2013, Vince Cianni interviewed gay men and women in the U.S. military, inviting them to recount their experiences of discrimination and acceptance in the military and after their service. These recordings are almost all with men. They are associated with Cianni's documentary book, Gays in the Military (2014).
  Digital audio WAV files taken from the original minidiscs are available for use. Transcriptions for portions of the interviews can be found in the "Interviews" section of the book Gays in the Military.
  - Affuso, John, 2010-06-20; 1
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0013)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0013)
  - Almy, Mike, 2010-05-08; 2
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0006)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0006)
  - Alva, Eric, 2011-08-28; 3
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0010)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0010)
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0009)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0009)
  - Barefoot, Don, 2010-08-10; 4
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0002)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0002)
  - Bramer, Don, circa 2011; 5
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0001)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0001)
  - Byrne, Chris, 2011-07-14; 6
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0001)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0001)
  - Chandlee, Will, 2010-06-09; 7
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0005)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0005)
  - Chapparell, Rob, 2011-06-19; 8
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0010)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0010)
  - Chism, Ray, 2010-06-24; 9
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0013)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0013)
  - Dobbs, Travis, 2010-09-25; 10
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0012)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0012)
  - Dodd, Paul, 2011-05-20; 11
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0010)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0010)
  - Dunning, Zoe, 2010-06-19; 12
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0007)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0007)
  - High, Ira, 2012-03-13; 13
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0009)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0009)
  - Key, Jeff, 2010-08-13; 14
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0003)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0003)
  - Lambert, Brian, circa 2011; 15
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0001)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0001)
  - Loverde, Tony, 2012-09-24; 16
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0011)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0011)
  - McCary, Matt and David Cochenic, 2011-08-24; 17
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0009)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0009)
  - Meyer, Denny, 2010-06-24; 18
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0005)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0005)
  - Michaels, Duane, 2012-04-15; 19
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0007)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0007)
  - O'Brien, John, 2010-05-08/2010-08-02; 20
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0006)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0006)
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0008)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0008)
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0005)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0005)
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0004)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0004)
  - Puckett, Greer, 2010-08-15; 21
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0003)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0003)
  - Reinhardt, Lee, 2010-09-25; 22
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0012)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0012)
  - Sheppe, Ken, 2012-03-14; 23
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0012)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0012)
  - Smith, Rob, 2010-08-02; 24
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0004)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0004)
  - Thomas, Hank, 2010-06-28; 25
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0008)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0008)
  - Thomas, Maylon, 2010-08-10; 26
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0002)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0002)
  - Zuniga, Joe, circa 2011; 27
    - Original minidisc recording (Box 22, Audio-disc RL10038-MD-0001)
    - WAV audio file(s) (Digital-materials RL10038-SET-0001, E-folder RL10038MD0001)